Jesus Acosta

Los Angeles, CA 91345

(818) 270-3591 | jesus.a.acosta@outlook.com | linkedin.com/in/jesusa-acosta

SUMMARY STATEMENT

Driven security guard with a strong military background who offers exceptional security services in ensuring the safety and security of high-profile government personnel and facilities. College-educated with three years of managerial experience working in Logistics, Security, and Interpersonal Relations. Strive to exceed professional and personal goals—strong written and verbal communication skills. Seeking a challenging role within Department of Defense agencies.

KEY QUALIFICATION

TOP SECRET SECURITY CLEARANCE	CUSTOMER SERVICE	MANAGEMENT
ATTENTION TO DETAIL	LEADERSHIP	TRAINING
COMMUNICATION	SUPERVISOR	SECURITY

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Non-Commissioned Officer United States Marine Corps December 2018 - October 2023

- Assisted the Detachment Commander in leading and managing a detachment of 7 Marines by stimulating morale and assigning tasks to each Marine with collateral duties.
- Mentored 3 Marines in improving professional and personal growth, assisted 4 Marines actively seeking off-duty education and taught two classes of applying first aid and CPR as required.
- Led 4 Marines overseas in support of Marine Rotational Force-Europe in Norway conducting multiple training exercises and coordinating troop movements with Norwegian military and convoys carrying critical equipment and passengers.

Marine Security Guard, Marine Corps Embassy Security Group Quantico, VA

October 2020 – June 2023

- Provided 2,286 hours of armed internal security for U.S. embassies and consulates worldwide, secured all
 classified materials, and challenged all personnel in unauthorized areas.
- Issued thirteen incident reports improving the Embassy/Consulate's overall security and safety and wrote 1 OF-117 security violation report documenting the improper storage of classified material.
- Collaborated in the planning and execution of the detachment's mission-oriented training to include 37
 response drills to improve the operational readiness of the detachment in preparation for various
 contingencies.

Motor Transportation Operator, Logistic Operations

March 2017 - October 2023

United States Marine Corps

- Operated with zero accidents and provided the required support, serving more than 60K personnel yearly.
- Managed \$3.4B in equipment and served as the unit's Dispatcher for Combat Logistics Company 36.

EDUCATION

Associate of Arts in General Studies, December 2018

University of Maryland Global Campus, Adelphi, MD

CERTIFICATIONS/ACHIEVEMENTS

Certificate of Appreciation

U.S. Consulate Karachi 2022

For contribution to public diplomacy service within the United States Mission Pakistan.

Certificate of Appreciation

Chargé d'Affaires Embassy San Jose, Costa Rica 2021

In support of the level 3 VIP visit (Secretary of State Anthony Blinken), which totaled 24 hours of security service during this event.

Oleoresin Capsicum Certification

Quantico, VA 2020

TRAINING

Norway

B.V. Course 2020

Germany

HAZMAT Course 2019

Japan

Jungle Warfare Training 2018

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE / COMMUNITY SERVICE

United Service Organizations

Japan and Metropolitan Washington-Baltimore Volunteered over 165 hours.

Department of State

U.S. Embassies and Consulates

Volunteered over 20 hours, which included color guard, host country marathon, Toys for Tots, events with the Public Affairs Section, and emergency preparedness fair.